今天你好
hello today
我将谈论PMPM和它的原因。
i'm going to talk about pmpm and the reason
它是如此的性能
it is so performance
我的名字是Zoton Zolton。
my name is zoton zolton question
你在乌克兰吗？
are you in ukraine
目前我的工作有点
currently i work for a bit
的管理。
for on depends management
在这之前，我为 "答案 "工作了大约9年。
before that i worked for just answer for about nine years
从2016年开始
and since 2016
我是pnpm的首席维护者。
i'm the lead maintainer of pnpm
在谈论pnpm之前，让我们简单地谈谈
before talking about pnpm let's briefly talk about
其他nogs软件包管理器
other nogs package managers
npm是第一个，也是
so npm was the first one and
它是最受欢迎的一个
it is the most popular one
在过去，它使用
in the past it used
nesta而不是更多的使用目录结构
nesta not more use directory structure
但是这种结构有很多缺点，比如说
but this structure had many disadvantageslike for instance
许多包是重复的
many packages were duplicated
里面没有模块
inside not modules
还有
and also
的
the
因为它使用了嵌套
because it uses used nesting
的目录
the directory
有时非常深
were sometimes very deep
而在窗口上，有
and on windows there was
窗口上有一个小时的时间
there were windows on one pass hours
为了解决这些问题，npm团队想出了
in order to solve these issues the npm team came up with
一种替代性的非模式结构
an alternative not modus structure
他们称之为
that they called
一个扁平的节点模型或吊挂的节点模型
a flat nod models or a hoisted nod models
他们在npm第三版中推出了这种结构。
and they shipped it in npm version three
在那个时候，Alexander google
around that time alexander google
想出了一个替代方法来解决
came up with an alternative approach to fix the
问题
issues
在嵌套而非模块上
over nested not modules
他的想法是使用模拟链接
his idea was to use sim links
因此，模拟链接允许创建
so sim links allowed to create
像
like
与你的高位嵌套，而不需要
with your tall nesting without
实际上是将目录嵌套到彼此之间
actually nesting directories into each other
这个想法后来被
this idea was then
被ricostacruz借用了，他用同样的方法创建了pnpm
borrowed by ricostacruz and he created pnpm
使用同样的方法，并且
using the same approach and
最近，我加入了pnpm，从那以后
recently afterwards i have joined pnpm and since then
从那时起，我就开始维护它
since then i'm maintaining it
稍后
a bit later
yarn被公开了，yarn是由facebook创建的，以解决
yarn was made public and yarn was created by facebook to solve
npm的一些其他问题，比如
some other issues of npm like
非终点站和速度
non terminus and speed
pm是由无政府组织提供的官方软件包管理器。
and pm is the official package manager shipped by no gs
在过去，它有一些人的问题，我说过
in the past it had man issues and i said
它是非确定性的
it was non deterministic
因为它没有一个锁文件，所以速度极慢
because it did not have a lock file it was extremely slow
而且
and
从最近开始，它就没有单体支持了
it had no monarical support since very recently
在牧师那里
in the pastor
我们管理橡树的不真实的可靠性和PM
we manage oaks about the unreal reliability of and pm
是Facebook创建的纱线
is facebook created yarn
自那时以来，它是由社区维护
since then it is maintained by the community
而且他们已经解决了
and they have solved
了npm的很多问题
a lot of the issues of npm
和
and
我认为它是一段时间内最好的软件包管理器
i think it was the best package manager for some time
从
from
其中，他们想出了一个激进的新方法来解决
in which they came up with a radical anew approach to solve
一些
some of the
的问题
issues with not modules
他们引入了即插即用
they introduced plug and play
默认情况下是打开的
which is on by default
这是一个
this is a
非常有趣的
very interesting
技术
technique
来管理父母，有人喜欢有人不喜欢
to manage the parents some love it some don't
自从第十六个版本以来，Nojs已经在
since version sixteen nojs ships
yarn与corpec
yarn with corpec
以及 pnpm，所以如果你使用 nojs 16th
as well as pnpm so if you use nojs sixteen
你可以将corpic启用并
you can round corpic enable and
yarn和pnpm都可以在你的系统中使用。
both yarn and a pnpm will be available in your
pnpm的创建者是
pin pm was created
完全由开放源代码的贡献者创建
completely by open source contributors
它的开发是
it was developed
围绕着这套
around the set
和yarn同时开发的
around the same time as yarn
所以它不是一个新的软件包管理器，而是
so it's not a new package manager it's
它和yarn一样古老，它实际上是
it's as old as yarn it was actually
比yarn更早公开
public earlier than yarn
而且
and
pnpm被很多伟大的公司所支持
pnpm is supported by a lot of great companies
例如，我的工作
for instance i work
现在有一点
for a bit now and
我的很多日常工作都与pnpm有关
a lot of my day to day tasks are related to pnpm
正如我所说，它是由no js提供的
and as i said it is shipped by no js
通过corpic
through corpic
所以它是一种官方的东西
so it's kind of official
以及yarn也是如此
as well as yarn as well
它有一定的正当性
it has some legitimacy to it
它在过去两年中获得了很大的发展。
it pm pm gains
在过去的两年里获得了大量的人气
gained a lot of popularity in the last two years
你可以看到下载的数量
as you can see the number of downloads
研究的增加
studied increases
而今年我们已经有
and this year we already have
比去年多三倍的下载量
three times more downloads than last year
我们有很多知名的大公司都在使用
and we have a lot of big well known companies that use
pnpm
所以我们来谈谈
so let's talk about
这个不是由PNPM创建的模式结构
this not modus structure that is created by pnpm
对不起，我没听清你的名字。
sorry i didn't catch your name e
正如你在左边看到的那样
as you can see on the left
你什么时候有一个项目只有一个
when did you have a project that has only one
单一的直接攻击性表达版本的项目
single direct depensive express version for
如果你运行和pm安装
if you run and pm install
并打开你的正常使用目录
and you open your normal use directory
你会看到所有这些不同的包都在那里，尽管
you will see all these different packages there even though
它们并不在你的部署中
they are not in your depenses
这是因为npm把所有的
this is because npm hoists all the
间接依赖是
indirect depends is
和
and
如果你是在pnpm上安装，并且你打开了node moduce
if you are on pnpm install and your open node moduce
你会看到只有这三个文件点 pnpm
you will see only those three files dot pnpm
dot moducem 和 express
dot moducem and express
而其中两个文件实际上是隐藏文件
and two of these files are actually hidden files
所以你将只得到你的直接依赖关系
so you will only get your direct dependency
在nod模块的根目录下
in the root of nod modules
作为结果，如果你在一个由npm维护的项目中导入cookie
as a result if you will import cookie
在一个由npm维护的项目中
in a project maintained by npm
你的代码就会工作
your code will work
因为cookie是挂在转子上的，而不是挂在moils上的。
because cookie is hoisted to the rotors not moils
而在pnpm中，这将无法工作
with pnpm this won't work
因为cookie是
because cookie is
在某个秘密的地方，我稍后会展示
in some secret placewhere i will show later
但这是一个非常危险的情况，因为
but this is a very dangerous situation because
如果你使用cookie，但不把它添加到你的依赖项中
if you will use cookie but you won't add it to your dependencies
可能会出现这样的情况：在某个较新的版本中，Express
it might happen that express in some newer version
在一个新的补丁版本中会停止使用cookie
in a new patch version will stop using cookie
而
and
结果是它不会
as a result it won't
它不会被提升到转子上，而不是Modus和
it won't be hoisted to the rotor not modus and
而你的代码将被破坏，即使你没有改变任何东西
and your code will break even though you did not change anything
这种情况不会发生，因为
this pm this won't happen because
你将不能够
you won't be able to
需要不在你的依赖关系中的依赖关系。
ever require the dependence that is not in your dependence
但如果不在根中，cookie在哪里呢？
but where is cookie if it's not in the root so actually
它隐藏在这个点 pnpm 之内。
it's hidden inside this dot pnpm further
pnpm将所有的依赖关系
pnpm places all the dependences
直接和在直接
direct and in direct
到dot pnpm内部的一个扁平目录结构中。
to a flat directory structure inside dot pnpm
中的扁平目录结构，而这些依赖关系则被
and the dependences are
链接到
linked into
这个孤立的子文件夹而不是模块文件夹中，使用模拟链接
this isolate sub not modules folders using sim links
所以实际上
so actually the
你在你的根目录中看到的快递
express that you see in the root of your
非模块
non modules
是，它只是一个连接到这个隐藏的Expresswater的缝隙链接
is that it's just a seam link to this hidden expresswater
在pm里面
inside pm
的cookie，而cookie则是
and cookie which is a depense of
Express是
express is
sim链接到express的专用非modus文件夹。
sim linked to the dedicated not modus folder of express
这一点
thisthis
孤立的not modus对单亲家庭来说是非常非常好的。
isolated not modus is very very good for monorepus
与非说唱歌手
with non rappers
如果你使用悬挂式非模态使用
if you use a hoisted non moil use
你的项目将不仅能够使用
your project will be able to use not just the
你的依赖关系的子依赖关系，而且还能使用任何其他项目的
your the sub dependencies of your dependencies but also any
任何其他项目的依赖性
dependencies of any other projects
正如你在这里看到的
as you can see here
who和bar都有一个依赖关系
both who and bar have one dependency
而且这两个依赖项都被
and both of these dependencies are
悬挂在他们的根目录下，而不是君主国的模块目录下
hoisted to their root not modules folder of your monarchy
因此，作为一个结果
so as a result
吧台
bar
将能够导入
will be able to import
的深度，尽管它既不是一个
depth of fu even though it's neither a
直接的北方和间接的依赖关系
direct northern and indirect dependency
吧的
of bar
所以
so
一旦你释放了bar
once you release bar
有人会安装它，它就会立即损坏
and someone will install it it will break immediately
用一个由pnpm创建的孤立的非moduce
with a with an isolated non moduce created by pnpm
这并不是一个问题，因为
this is not a problem because
你只得到你的
you only get your
直接依赖的吊车
direct dependence's hoist
sim链接到nod modus
sim linked to nod modus
而且
and
实际上没有任何东西被浪费到根节点模块的快速文件夹中。
nothing is actually wasted to the root node module's fast folder
你的mono苹果的
of your mono apple
所有的子程序
all the sub depenances
都隐藏在stockpian can文件夹中
are hidden inside the stockpian can folder
所以满
so full
将无法
will not be able to
要求依赖mono应用程序中的其他项目
require depends of other projects in the mono app
你可能会问为什么其他软件包管理器不使用这种方法？
you might ask why other package managers don't use this approach
好吧
well
实际上
actually
pm
想要添加pm start而不是modus目录
wants to add the pm start not modus directory
作为一个选项，因为这个问题是monorepos
as an option because of this issues is monorepos
但这种方法目前有一些缺点，因为
but this approach has some disadvantages currently because
有些脚趾不喜欢simlings，比如react native
some toes don't like simlings like react native
根本就不能和simlings一起工作
doesn't work with simlings at all
和许多
and many
生态系统中的许多包都是
many packages in the ecosystem are
发布的软件包都有这种缺陷
published with this broken
导入语句，导入
import statements that import
间接依赖关系
indirect dependences
所以这些粘性的非模块会被破坏
so these stick non modules breaks
嗯
破坏了许多软件包
breaks many packages
但是
however
pnpm
有一些变通方法，所以你不会有第三个问题。
has some workarounds so you will never have the third issue
如果你必须使用seamlings来工作
and if you have to set on to work with seamlings
那么
then
你可以使用节点链接或吊装吊装设置
you can use the node link or hoisted hoisted setting
并且pnpm将创建一个传统的
and the pmpm will create a traditional
悬挂式或其他被称为
hoisted or otherwise known as
铂金模块
platinum modules
所以，PMPM已经覆盖了你，你可以在任何类型的项目中使用它。
so pmpm has you covered you can use it with any kind of project
另一个问题
another issue
pnpm的另一个原因是它的性能非常好。
another reason pnpm is so performance is because it
非常非常有效地使用这个空间
uses this space very very efficiently
你可能已经注意到，当你使用npm或yarn时，你的非模块会消耗大量的空间。
you might have noticed that your not modules consumes a lot of
你可能已经注意到，当你使用npm或yarn时，你的非模块会消耗很多空间
space when you use npm or yarn
如果你有十几个或二十几个
and if you have like ten or twenty
如果你的电脑上有十个或二十个项目，那么
just with projects on your pc then
如果你的电脑上有十个或二十个项目，那么你的依赖性可能会消耗像10
your depends this might consume like ten
二三十G的空间
twenty thirty gigabytes on this space
这实际上不是pnpm的问题
this is actually not an issue with pnpm
因为pnpm使用一个中央
because pnpm uses a central
内容可寻址存储
content addressable storage
来链接你所依赖的文件，并没有更多的用途。
to link the files of your dependence is not more use
内容可寻址存储器基本上就是
a content addressable storage is basically
一个存储文件的目录
a directory where files are stored
的位置上计算出的
at locations calculated
的位置。
from the
文件的内容计算出来的位置。
contents of these files
这意味着，例如，如果你有三个
this means that for instance if you have three
个版本的软件包
versions of a single package
并且所有这些
and all this
版本的软件包都有一个
versions of the package have a file
没有变化
with no changes
然后pmpm实际上会
and then pmpm will actually
只把这个文件写到磁盘上一次，然后
write this file only once to the disc and
点
point
并且无论何时安装这个软件包
and anytime this packages are installed
它不会创建这个火的新副本
it will not create a new copy of this fires
pmpm将只是创建
pmpm will just create
一个硬
a hard
链接到内容可调存储中的一个位置
link to a single location in the content adjustable storage
所以实际上在你的mod模块中，在这个垂直存储中
so actually inside your mod modules inside this vertical store
每个文件都被指定到中央的一个位置上
every file is just appointed to a location in the central
内容可寻址的存储空间
content adressable store
正如你在这里看到的那样，我们有
as you can see here like we have
项目A和项目B以及
project a and project b and
一些文件
some of the files
在这两个项目中是相同的
in these two projects are the same
所以它们都指向光盘上的同一个位置
so they they point to the same location on the disc
所以我们不需要告诉
so we don't tell
一个文件的两份副本，我们只有一份文件的副本被写入光盘
two copies of a file we have only one copy of the file written
到光盘上
to the disc
因此，当你
as a result when you
每次你在
each time you around
pm安装在一个新项目中
pm install in a new project
pnpm
只会在你的磁盘上多消耗一点空间，不像
consumes just a little more space on your disk unlike
npm或yarn
npm or yarn which
你不会使用一个
you don't use a
默认情况下，内容可寻址存储
content addressable store by default
所以你可以看到在第一次安装时
so you can see on the first install
pnpm使用的磁盘空间与按钮的数量差不多
pnpm uses around the same amount of disk space buttons
在随后的项目中，当围绕pnpm安装时，它将
in a subsequent project when around pnpm install it will
它不会再消耗
it will not consume
那巨大的空间
that huge amount of space again
因为这些文件已经在商店里了，而且
because the files are already in the store and
pm只是创建新的硬盘，而不是复制
pm just creates new hardings not copies
实际上，一个
actually a
纱线开始使用
yarn started to use
一个内容可寻址的存储，以及
a content addressable store as well
作为目前的一个OP 10功能
as an op ten feature for now
他们计划在下一个主要版本中使其
and they plan to make it
他们计划在下一个主要版本中默认使用。
on by default in the next major version
如果你看了我们的基准测试
if you have looked at our benchmarks
你可能已经注意到
you have might have noticed that
在某些情况下，pnpm
in some scenarios pnpm is
比npm快好几倍，甚至
several times faster than an npm and even
比yarn快
faster than yarn
这个呃
this uh
pnpm更快的原因是
the reason pnpm is faster is
因为它使用了一种不同的算法来解决和获取
because it uses a different algorithm to resolve and fetch
依赖，所以npm和yarn都有独立的阶段来进行
dependencies so both npm and yarn have separate stages for
第一阶段的安装
installation at the first stage
所有的依赖关系都已解决
all the dependencies are resolved
在
on
第二阶段，所有的防御措施都从注册表中获取。
the second stage all the defenses are fetched from the registry
在最后的第三阶段
and at the last third stage
所有的包都被写入模块中
all the packages are written to not modules
不像pm和
unlike and pm and
yarnpnpm没有这个独立的阶段
yarnpnpm doesn't have this separate stages
它实际上试图在同一时间做
it actually tries to do
所有的事情都在同一时间进行
everything concurrently at the same time
所以
so
当它解决了一个软件包
when it resolves a package
它立即开始从注册表中获取它
it immediately starts to fetch it from the registry
它不会等待所有其他的软件包被解析。
it doesn't wait for all the other packages to be resolved
这是非常有效的，当
this is very efficient and when
时
when
它开始编写
it starts to write
时，快速模式的模块就会立即开始，当它们的最后一个
fast mode modules immediately when they last
包被解决
package is resolved
但它并不等待软件包被取走
but it doesn't wait for packages to be fetched
一些
some
一些软件包正在
some packages are
仍在被取走
still being fetched
而另一些已经被写入非非模块中了
and some others are already written to non non modules
你可能会问为什么其他软件包管理器不
you might ask why other package managers don't
很好地使用这种技术
use this technique well
这听起来是个好主意
that sounds like a great idea
这种算法实际上是非常复杂的，可能
this algorithm actually is very complex and probably
一些软件包管理员更喜欢
some package managers prefer
要慢一点，但要
be a bit slower but to
拥有更容易维护的代码
have code that is easier to maintain
而且对于新的贡献者来说更容易学习
and easier to learn for new contributors
当然还有一些速度上的改进
and some of the speed improvements are of course
因为我们使用了一个内容可寻址存储
possible because we use a content addressable store
因为我们使用了一个可寻址的内容库，而且我们使用了一个不同的正常使用方法来进行重组。
and because we use a different normal use there to restructure
现在这都是关于pnpm的速度，我只想提一下
now this is all about pnpm speed and i just want to mention
可能不是很广泛的pnpm的非功能
probably not wide the non feature of pnpm
你实际上可以用pnpm来管理没有GS的版本
you can actually use pnpm to manage no GS versions
所以你可以用pnpm来代替nvs、nvm或water
so you can use pnpm instead of nvs or nvm or water
有一个命令 pnpm 和 views
there is a command pnpm and views
你可以运行它来安装no js
which you can run to install no js
因此，例如，如果你想
so for instance if you want to
安装no js 16，只需运行p、pm和views即可。
install no js sixteen just run p and pm and views
dash global 16
你就会在你的网站上看到no js sixteen。
and you will have no js sixteen in your
pmpm有很多很多的功能，你可以打开我们的
pmpm has lots lots of features you can open up our
网站 pmpm dot io 并
website pmpm dot io and
打开功能比较页面，你会看到这个表格。
open the feature comparison pageyou will see this table
但你可以看到，我们已经实现了
but you can see that we have implemented
几乎所有的功能，包括
almost all the features that
yarn或npm hell
yarn or npm hell
的所有功能，而且我们拥有yarn和npm hell的所有单元功能。
and we have all unit features that neither yarn
到现在为止，npm也没有
nor npm have as of now
像副作用的现金或
like side effects cashor
管理不只是版本
managing not just versions
谢谢
thanks
谢谢你听我的演讲
for listening to my presentation
请访问pnpm io
please visit pnpm io
给予我们的回帖星
give our reposterior star
并在twitter上关注我们：pnpm js
and also follow us on twitter at pnpm js
并在twitter上关注我，我是一个思考问题的人。
and follow me on twitter i'm a thought on the question
谢谢你，再见
thanks bye